<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Worldbuildings on</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/</link><description>Recent content in Worldbuildings on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Food Menu</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Food-Menu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Food-Menu/</guid><description>About I wanted to make some list of menu for a place characters might travel to:
Menu Baked potatoes with goat cheese Porridge Roasted quail Bear flank steak Steak Milk, goat Milk, cow Meat pie Roasted boar Pork ribs Venison steak</description></item><item><title>Random Buildings</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Random-Buildings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Random-Buildings/</guid><description>Random Buildings Pulse-pounding chases and harrowing escapes within the confines of a town or city can sometimes force characters to dash into buildings.</description></item><item><title>Trinkets Table</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Trinkets-Table/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Trinkets-Table/</guid><description> Trinket A mummified goblin hand A piece of crystal that faintly glows in the moonlight A gold coin minted in an unknown land A diary written in a language you don’t know A brass ring that never tarnishes An old chess piece made from glass A pair of knucklebone dice, each with a skull symbol on the side that would normally show six pips A small idol depicting a nightmarish creature that gives you unsettling dreams when you sleep near it A rope necklace from which dangles four mummified elf fingers The deed for a parcel of land in a realm unknown to you A 1-ounce block made from an unknown material A small cloth doll skewered with needles A tooth from an unknown beast An enormous scale, perhaps from a dragon A bright green feather An old divination card bearing your likeness A glass orb filled with moving smoke A 1-pound egg with a bright red shell A pipe that blows bubbles A glass jar containing a weird bit of flesh floating in pickling fluid A tiny gnome-crafted music box that plays a song you dimly remember from your childhood A small wooden statuette of a smug halfling A brass orb etched with strange runes A multicolored stone disk A tiny silver icon of a raven A bag containing forty-seven humanoid teeth, one of which is rotten A shard of obsidian that always feels warm to the touch A dragon&amp;rsquo;s bony talon hanging from a plain leather necklace A pair of old socks A blank book whose pages refuse to hold ink, chalk, graphite, or any other substance or marking A silver badge in the shape of a five-pointed star A knife that belonged to a relative A glass vial filled with nail clippings A rectangular metal device with two tiny metal cups on one end that throws sparks when wet A white, sequined glove sized for a human A vest with one hundred tiny pockets A small, weightless stone block A tiny sketch portrait of a goblin An empty glass vial that smells of perfume when opened A gemstone that looks like a lump of coal when examined by anyone but you A scrap of cloth from an old banner A rank insignia from a lost legionnaire A tiny silver bell without a clapper A mechanical canary inside a gnome-crafted lamp A tiny chest carved to look like it has numerous feet on the bottom A dead sprite inside a clear glass bottle A metal can that has no opening but sounds as if it is filled with liquid, sand, spiders, or broken glass (your choice) A glass orb filled with water, in which swims a clockwork goldfish A silver spoon with an M engraved on the handle A whistle made from gold-colored wood A dead scarab beetle the size of your hand Two toy soldiers, one with a missing head A small box filled with different-sized buttons A candle that can’t be lit A tiny cage with no door An old key An indecipherable treasure map A hilt from a broken sword A rabbit’s foot A glass eye A cameo carved in the likeness of a hideous person A silver skull the size of a coin An alabaster mask A pyramid of sticky black incense that smells very bad A nightcap that, when worn, gives you pleasant dreams A single caltrop made from bone A gold monocle frame without the lens A 1-inch cube, each side painted a different color A crystal knob from a door A small packet filled with pink dust A fragment of a beautiful song, written as musical notes on two pieces of parchment A silver teardrop earring made from a real teardrop The shell of an egg painted with scenes of human misery in disturbing detail A fan that, when unfolded, shows a sleeping cat A set of bone pipes A four-leaf clover pressed inside a book discussing manners and etiquette A sheet of parchment upon which is drawn a complex mechanical contraption An ornate scabbard that fits no blade you have found so far An invitation to a party where a murder happened A bronze pentacle with an etching of a rat&amp;rsquo;s head in its center A purple handkerchief embroidered with the name of a powerful archmage Half of a floorplan for a temple, castle, or some other structure A bit of folded cloth that, when unfolded, turns into a stylish cap A receipt of deposit at a bank in a far-flung city A diary with seven missing pages An empty silver snuffbox bearing an inscription on the surface that says &amp;ldquo;dreams&amp;rdquo; An iron holy symbol devoted to an unknown god A book that tells the story of a legendary hero&amp;rsquo;s rise and fall, with the last chapter missing A vial of dragon blood An ancient arrow of elven design A needle that never bends An ornate brooch of dwarven design An empty wine bottle bearing a pretty label that says, &amp;ldquo;The Wizard of Wines Winery, Red Dragon Crush, 331422-W&amp;rdquo; A mosaic tile with a multicolored, glazed surface A petrified mouse A black pirate flag adorned with a dragon&amp;rsquo;s skull and crossbones A tiny mechanical crab or spider that moves about when it’s not being observed A glass jar containing lard with a label that reads, &amp;ldquo;Griffon Grease&amp;rdquo; A wooden box with a ceramic bottom that holds a living worm with a head on each end of its body A metal urn containing the ashes of a hero ^table</description></item><item><title>Urban Encounters</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Urban-Encounters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Urban-Encounters/</guid><description>Animals on the Loose. The character see one or more unexpected animals loose in the street. This challenge could be anything from a pack of baboons to an escaped circus bear, tiger, or elephant.</description></item><item><title>Weather</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Weather/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Weather/</guid><description> [!info] Weather
Temperature: dice: [[Weather#^temperature]]|Temperature
Wind: dice:[[Weather#^wind]]|Wind
Precipitation: dice:[[Weather#^precipitation]]|Precipitation
dice: 1d20 Temperature 1-14 Normal for the season 15-17 dice: 1d4*10 F colder than normal 18-20 dice: 1d4*10 F hotter than normal ^temperature dice:1d20 Wind 1-12 No Wind 13-17 Light Wind 18-20 Strong Wind ^wind dice:1d20 Precipitation 1-12 No Rain 13-17 Light precipitation 18-20 Heavy precipitation ^precipitation</description></item><item><title>NPC Trait Table</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/NPC-Trait-Table/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/NPC-Trait-Table/</guid><description>[!info]+ NPC Trait Generator
High Ability: dice: [[NPC Trait Table#^abilities]]|High Ability Low Ability: dice: [[NPC Trait Table#^abilities]]|Low Ability Age: dice: [[NPC Trait Table#^age]]</description></item><item><title>Settlement Generator</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Settlements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Tables/Settlements/</guid><description>Settlements 1 A village, town, or city makes an excellent backdrop for an adventure. The adventurers might be called on to track down a criminal who&amp;rsquo;s gone into hiding, solve a murder, take out a gang of wererats or doppelgangers, or protect a settlement under siege.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Warfare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Warfare/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Magic</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic/</guid><description>These are some of the questions I ask myself when I&amp;rsquo;m creating magic for my world. I personally like magic with rules rather than leaving it to be mystical.</description></item><item><title>Magic and Fundamentals</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Fundamentals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Fundamentals/</guid><description>Is there some sort of rules in your world about magic like laws of thermodynamics? A good example is from Full Metal Alchemist; laws of equilibrant exchange.</description></item><item><title>Worldbuilding - Magic and Culture</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Culture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Culture/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Worldbuilding - Magic and Economy</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Economy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Economy/</guid><description>Just like any resources and tools in our world, it would impact the economics of your world. Would they be rich if they can use magic because they can do more?</description></item><item><title>Worldbuilding - Magic and Fauna</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Fauna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Fauna/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Worldbuilding - Magic and Geography</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Geography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Geography/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Worldbuilding - Magic and Knowledge</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Knowledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Knowledge/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Worldbuilding - Magic and Politics</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Politics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Politics/</guid><description>And regulation entails organizational effectiveness, a chain of command, and a structure for logistical support.
- Sun Tzu</description></item><item><title>Worldbuilding - Magic and Religion</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Religion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Religion/</guid><description>Magic might be perceived as mysticism or different from divine power from deities. Here are some questions to fill in the gaps.</description></item><item><title>Worldbuilding - Magic and Technology</title><link>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Technology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jethoof.github.io/home/worldbuilding/Worldbuilding-Magic-and-Technology/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>